We see with the eyes.
[AI] 我们用眼睛看。
but we see with the brain as well.
[AI] 但我们也可以通过大脑看到。
And seeing with the brain is often called imagination.
[AI] 用大脑看东西通常被称为想象。
And we are familiar with the landscapes of our own imagination.
[AI] 我们熟悉自己想象中的风景。
our inscapes.
[AI] 我们的构成要素。
We've lived with them all our lives.
[AI] 我们一辈子都和他们住在一起。
But there are also hallucinations as well.
[AI] 但也有幻觉。
And hallucinations are completely different.
[AI] 而幻觉则完全不同。
They don't seem to be of our creation.
[AI] 它们似乎不是我们创造的。
They don't seem to be under control.
[AI] 他们似乎没有受到控制。
They seem to come from the outside and to mimic perception.
[AI] 它们似乎来自外部，模仿感知。
So I am going to be talking about hallucinations
[AI] 所以我要说的是幻觉
and a particular sort of visual hallucination.
[AI] 还有一种特殊的视觉幻觉。
which I see among my patients.
[AI] 我在我的病人中看到的。
A few months ago. I got a phone call from a nursing home where I work.
[AI] 几个月前。我接到我工作的养老院打来的电话。
They told me that one of their residents. an old lady in her 90s.
[AI] 他们告诉我他们的一个居民。一位90多岁的老太太。
was seeing things.
[AI] 我在看东西。
and they wondered if she'd gone bonkers
[AI] 他们想知道她是不是疯了
or. because she was an old lady.
[AI] 或因为她是个老太太。
whether she'd had a stroke. or whether she had Alzheimer's.
[AI] 她是否中风了。或者她是否患有老年痴呆症。
And so they asked me if I would come and see Rosalie.
[AI] 所以他们问我是否愿意来看罗莎莉。
the old lady.
[AI] 老太太。
I went in to see her.
[AI] 我进去看她。
It was evident straightaway that she was perfectly sane
[AI] 很明显，她是完全清醒的
and lucid and of good intelligence.
[AI] 头脑清醒，智力良好。
but she'd been very startled and very bewildered.
[AI] 但她感到非常震惊和困惑。
because she'd been seeing things.
[AI] 因为她一直在看东西。
And she told me -- the nurses hadn't mentioned this --
[AI] 她告诉我，护士们没有提到这件事--
that she was blind.
[AI] 她是瞎的。
that she had been completely blind from macular degeneration for five years.
[AI] 她因为黄斑变性已经完全失明五年了。
But now. for the last few days. she'd been seeing things.
[AI] 但是现在。在过去的几天里。她一直在看事情。
So I said. "What sort of things?"
[AI] 所以我说。“什么事？”
And she said. "People in Eastern dress.
[AI] 她说。“穿着东方服装的人。
in drapes. walking up and down stairs.
[AI] 披着窗帘。上下楼梯。
A man who turns towards me and smiles.
[AI] 一个转向我微笑的男人。
but he has huge teeth on one side of his mouth.
[AI] 但他嘴巴的一边长着巨大的牙齿。
Animals too.
[AI] 动物也是。
I see a white building. It's snowing. a soft snow.
[AI] 我看见一座白色的建筑物。下雪了。柔软的雪。
I see this horse with a harness. dragging the snow away.
[AI] 我看见这匹马带着马具。把雪拖走。
Then. one night. the scene changes.
[AI] 然后一个晚上。场景发生了变化。
I see cats and dogs walking towards me.
[AI] 我看见猫和狗朝我走来。
They come to a certain point and then stop.
[AI] 他们到达某一点，然后停下来。
Then it changes again.
[AI] 然后它又变了。
I see a lot of children. They're walking up and down stairs.
[AI] 我看到很多孩子。他们在上下楼梯。
They wear bright colors. rose and blue.
[AI] 他们穿着鲜艳的颜色。玫瑰和蓝色。
like Eastern dress."
[AI] 我喜欢东方服装。"
Sometimes. she said. before the people come on.
[AI] 有时她说。在人们来之前。
she may hallucinate pink and blue squares on the floor.
[AI] 她可能会在地板上出现粉红色和蓝色的方块。
which seem to go up to the ceiling.
[AI] 这似乎达到了最高点。
I said. "Is this like a dream?"
[AI] 我说。“这像梦吗？”
And she said. "No. it's not like a dream. It's like a movie."
[AI] 她说。“不，它不像梦，它像电影。”
She said. "It's got color. It's got motion.
[AI] 她说。“它有颜色，有动感。
But it's completely silent. like a silent movie."
[AI] 但它是完全沉默的。就像一部无声电影。"
And she said it's a rather boring movie.
[AI] 她说这是一部相当无聊的电影。
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
She said. "All these people with Eastern dress.
[AI] 她说。“所有这些穿着东方服装的人。
walking up and down. very repetitive. very limited."
[AI] 走来走去。非常重复。非常有限。"
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
And she had a sense of humor.
[AI] 她有幽默感。
She knew it was a hallucination. but she was frightened.
[AI] 她知道这是一种幻觉。但是她很害怕。
She had lived 95 years.
[AI] 她活了95岁。
and she'd never had a hallucination before.
[AI] 她以前从未有过幻觉。
She said that the hallucinations were unrelated to anything she was thinking
[AI] 她说幻觉与她所想的一切无关
or feeling or doing.
[AI] 或者感觉或者做。
that they seemed to come on by themselves. or disappear.
[AI] 他们似乎是自己来的。或者消失。
She had no control over them.
[AI] 她无法控制他们。
She said she didn't recognize any of the people or places
[AI] 她说她不认识任何人或地方
in the hallucinations.
[AI] 在幻觉中。
and none of the people or the animals --
[AI] 没有人和动物--
well. they all seemed oblivious of her.
[AI] 好他们似乎都忘记了她。
And she didn't know what was going on.
[AI] 她不知道发生了什么。
She wondered if she was going mad or losing her mind.
[AI] 她不知道自己是疯了还是疯了。
Well. I examined her carefully.
[AI] 好我仔细地检查了她。
She was a bright old lady.
[AI] 她是个聪明的老太太。
perfectly sane.
[AI] 完全清醒。
She had no medical problems.
[AI] 她没有医疗问题。
She wasn't on any medications which could produce hallucinations.
[AI] 她没有服用任何可能产生幻觉的药物。
But she was blind.
[AI] 但她是瞎的。
And I then said to her. "I think I know what you have."
[AI] 然后我对她说。“我想我知道你有什么。”
I said. "There is a special form of visual hallucination
[AI] 我说。“有一种特殊形式的视觉幻觉
which may go with deteriorating vision or blindness.
[AI] 这可能伴随视力恶化或失明。
This was originally described." I said.
[AI] 这是最初描述的。”我说。
"right back in the 18th century.
[AI] “早在18世纪。
by a man called Charles Bonnet.
[AI] 一个叫查尔斯·邦尼的人。
And you have Charles Bonnet syndrome.
[AI] 你有查尔斯·博内特综合症。
There's nothing wrong with your brain. There's nothing wrong with your mind.
[AI] 你的大脑没有问题。你的脑子没问题。
You have Charles Bonnet syndrome."
[AI] 你得了查尔斯·博内特综合症。"
And she was very relieved at this.
[AI] 她对此感到非常欣慰。
that there was nothing seriously the matter.
[AI] 这件事并不严重。
and also rather curious.
[AI] 也很好奇。
She said. "Who is this Charles Bonnet?"
[AI] 她说。“这位查尔斯·邦尼是谁？”
She said. "Did he have them himself?"
[AI] 她说。“是他自己弄的吗？”
And she said. "Tell all the nurses that I have Charles Bonnet syndrome."
[AI] 她说。“告诉所有护士我得了查尔斯·博内特综合症。”
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
"I'm not crazy. I'm not demented. I have Charles Bonnet syndrome."
[AI] “我没有疯。我没有精神错乱。我有查尔斯·博内特综合症。”
Well. so. I did tell the nurses.
[AI] 好所以我确实告诉了护士们。
Now this. for me. is a common situation.
[AI] 现在这个。为了我。这是一种常见的情况。
I work in old-age homes. largely.
[AI] 我在养老院工作。主要地
I see a lot of elderly people
[AI] 我看到很多老人
who are hearing-impaired or visually impaired.
[AI] 听力受损或视力受损的人。
About 10 percent of the hearing-impaired people
[AI] 大约10%的听力受损者
get musical hallucinations.
[AI] 产生音乐幻觉。
And about 10 percent of the visually impaired people
[AI] 大约10%的视障人士
get visual hallucinations.
[AI] 产生视觉幻觉。
You don't have to be completely blind.
[AI] 你不必完全失明。
only sufficiently impaired.
[AI] 只有充分受损。
Now. with the original description in the 18th century.
[AI] 现在与18世纪的原始描述一致。
Charles Bonnet did not have them.
[AI] 查尔斯·邦尼没有。
His grandfather had these hallucinations.
[AI] 他的祖父有这些幻觉。
His grandfather was a magistrate. an elderly man.
[AI] 他的祖父是一名地方法官。老人。
He'd had cataract surgery.
[AI] 他做过白内障手术。
His vision was pretty poor.
[AI] 他的视力很差。
And in 1759. he described to his grandson
[AI] 1759年。他向他的孙子描述
various things he was seeing.
[AI] 他看到了各种各样的东西。
The first thing he said was he saw a handkerchief in midair.
[AI] 他说的第一句话是他在半空中看到一块手帕。
It was a large blue handkerchief with four orange circles.
[AI] 那是一块有四个橙色圆圈的蓝色大手帕。
And he knew it was a hallucination.
[AI] 他知道这是一种幻觉。
You don't have handkerchiefs in midair.
[AI] 你在半空中没有手帕。
And then he saw a big wheel in midair.
[AI] 然后他看到半空中有一个大轮子。
But sometimes he wasn't sure whether he was hallucinating or not.
[AI] 但有时他不确定自己是否产生幻觉。
because the hallucinations would fit in the context of the visions.
[AI] 因为幻觉与幻觉的背景相符。
So on one occasion. when his granddaughters were visiting them.
[AI] 所以有一次。当他的孙女们来看他们的时候。
he said. "And who are these handsome young men with you?"
[AI] 他说。“和你在一起的这些英俊的年轻人是谁？”
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
And they said. "Alas. Grandpapa. there are no handsome young men."
[AI] 他们说。“唉，爷爷，没有英俊的年轻人。”
And then the handsome young men disappeared.
[AI] 然后英俊的年轻人消失了。
It's typical of these hallucinations
[AI] 这是典型的幻觉
that they may come in a flash and disappear in a flash.
[AI] 他们可能会在瞬间到来，然后在瞬间消失。
They don't usually fade in and out.
[AI] 它们通常不会淡入淡出。
They are rather sudden. and they change suddenly.
[AI] 它们相当突然。他们突然改变了。
Charles Lullin. the grandfather.
[AI] 查尔斯·卢林。祖父。
saw hundreds of different figures.
[AI] 看到了数百个不同的数字。
different landscapes of all sorts.
[AI] 各种不同的风景。
On one occasion. he saw a man in a bathrobe smoking a pipe.
[AI] 有一次。他看见一个穿着浴衣的人在抽烟斗。
and realized it was himself.
[AI] 意识到是他自己。
That was the only figure he recognized.
[AI] 那是他唯一认识的人。
On one occasion. when he was walking in the streets of Paris.
[AI] 有一次。当他走在巴黎街头时。
he saw -- this was real -- a scaffolding.
[AI] 他看到——这是真的——一个脚手架。
But when he got back home. he saw a miniature of the scaffolding.
[AI] 但是当他回到家的时候。他看到了脚手架的一个缩影。
six inches high.
[AI] 六英寸高。
on his study table.
[AI] 在他的书桌上。
This repetition of perception is sometimes called "palinopsia."
[AI] 这种感知的重复有时被称为“palinopsia”
With him and with Rosalie.
[AI] 和他还有罗莎莉。
what seems to be going on --
[AI] 发生了什么事--
and Rosalie said. "What's going on?" --
[AI] 罗莎莉说。“怎么回事？”--
and I said that as you lose vision.
[AI] 我说过当你失去视力的时候。
as the visual parts of the brain are no longer getting any input.
[AI] 因为大脑的视觉部分不再获得任何输入。
they become hyperactive and excitable.
[AI] 他们变得极度活跃和兴奋。
and they start to fire spontaneously.
[AI] 它们开始自发地开火。
And you start to see things.
[AI] 你开始看到一些东西。
The things you see can be very complicated indeed.
[AI] 你所看到的东西确实很复杂。
With another patient of mine who also had some vision.
[AI] 我的另一个病人也有视力。
the visions she had could be disturbing.
[AI] 她看到的景象可能令人不安。
On one occasion. she said she saw a man in a striped shirt in a restaurant.
[AI] 有一次。她说她在一家餐馆看到一个穿着条纹衬衫的男人。
And he turned round.
[AI] 他转过身来。
and then he divided into six figures in striped shirts.
[AI] 然后他穿着条纹衬衫分成了六个人。
who started walking towards her.
[AI] 她开始向她走去。
And then the six figures came together. like a concertina.
[AI] 然后这六个数字加起来。就像一支协奏曲。
Once. when she was driving.
[AI] 一旦当她开车的时候。
or rather. her husband was driving.
[AI] 或者更确切地说。她丈夫在开车。
the road divided into four
[AI] 这条路分成四段
and she felt herself going simultaneously up four roads.
[AI] 她感到自己同时走上了四条路。
She had very mobile hallucinations as well.
[AI] 她也有非常活跃的幻觉。
A lot of them had to do with a car.
[AI] 他们中的很多人都与汽车有关。
Sometimes she would see a teenage boy sitting on the hood of the car.
[AI] 有时她会看到一个十几岁的男孩坐在汽车的引擎盖上。
He was very tenacious.
[AI] 他非常顽强。
and he moved rather gracefully when the car turned.
[AI] 当汽车转弯时，他动作相当优雅。
And then when they came to a stop.
[AI] 然后当他们停下来的时候。
the boy would do a sudden vertical takeoff. 100 foot in the air.
[AI] 这个男孩会突然垂直起飞。100英尺高。
and then disappear.
[AI] 然后消失。
Another patient of mine had a different sort of hallucination.
[AI] 我的另一个病人有一种不同的幻觉。
This was a woman who didn't have trouble with her eyes
[AI] 这是一个眼睛没有问题的女人
but the visual parts of her brain.
[AI] 但是她大脑的视觉部分。
a little tumor in the occipital cortex.
[AI] 枕骨皮质的一个小肿瘤。
And. above all. she would see cartoons.
[AI] 和首先她会看卡通片。
And these cartoons would be transparent.
[AI] 这些卡通是透明的。
and would cover half the visual field. like a screen.
[AI] 可以覆盖半个视野。像屏幕一样。
And especially. she saw cartoons of Kermit the Frog.
[AI] 尤其是。她看了青蛙克米特的卡通片。
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
Now. I don't watch Sesame Street.
[AI] 现在我不看《芝麻街》。
but she made a point of saying.
[AI] 但她说得很有道理。
"Why Kermit?" she said. "Kermit the Frog means nothing to me."
[AI] “为什么是科米特？”她说。“青蛙克米特对我来说毫无意义。”
You know. I was wondering about Freudian determinants: Why Kermit?
[AI] 你知道的。我想知道弗洛伊德的决定因素：为什么是科米特？
"Kermit the Frog means nothing to me."
[AI] “青蛙克米特对我来说毫无意义。”
She didn't mind the cartoons too much.
[AI] 她并不太在意那些卡通画。
But what did disturb her
[AI] 但是什么事使她不安呢
was she got very persistent images or hallucinations of faces.
[AI] 她有很持久的图像或脸的幻觉。
and as with Rosalie. the faces were often deformed.
[AI] 和罗莎莉一样。脸经常变形。
with very large teeth or very large eyes.
[AI] 有非常大的牙齿或非常大的眼睛。
And these frightened her.
[AI] 这些使她害怕。
Well. what is going on with these people?
[AI] 好这些人怎么了？
As a physician. I have to try and define what's going on
[AI] 作为一名医生。我必须试着去定义发生了什么
and to reassure people.
[AI] 让人们放心。
especially to reassure them that they're not going insane.
[AI] 特别是为了让他们确信他们不会发疯。
Something like 10 percent. as I said.
[AI] 大约10%。正如我所说。
of visually impaired people get these.
[AI] 很多视力受损的人都能得到这些。
But no more than one percent of the people acknowledge them.
[AI] 但只有不到百分之一的人承认他们。
because they are afraid they will be seen as insane or something.
[AI] 因为他们担心自己会被视为精神错乱之类的。
And if they do mention them to their own doctors.
[AI] 如果他们真的向自己的医生提起了。
they may be misdiagnosed.
[AI] 他们可能被误诊。
In particular. the notion is that if you see things or hear things.
[AI] 特别地。这个概念是，如果你看到或听到的东西。
you're going mad.
[AI] 你快疯了。
But the psychotic hallucinations are quite different.
[AI] 但是精神病性幻觉是完全不同的。
Psychotic hallucinations. whether they are visual or vocal.
[AI] 精神幻觉。无论是视觉上的还是声音上的。
they address you.
[AI] 他们称呼你。
They accuse you. they seduce you. they humiliate you. they jeer at you.
[AI] 他们指责你。他们引诱你。他们羞辱你。他们嘲笑你。
You interact with them.
[AI] 你与他们互动。
There is none of this quality of being addressed
[AI] 这些问题都没有得到解决
with these Charles Bonnet hallucinations.
[AI] 伴随着这些查尔斯·邦尼的幻觉。
There is a film. You're seeing a film which has nothing to do with you --
[AI] 有一部电影。你正在看一部与你无关的电影--
or that's how people think about it.
[AI] 或者人们就是这么想的。
There is also a rare thing called temporal lobe epilepsy.
[AI] 还有一种罕见的东西叫做颞叶癫痫。
and sometimes. if one has this.
[AI] 有时候。如果有这个。
one may feel oneself transported back to a time and place in the past.
[AI] 一个人可能会觉得自己回到了过去的某个时间和地点。
You're at a particular road junction.
[AI] 你在一个特定的路口。
You smell chestnuts roasting.
[AI] 你闻到烤栗子的味道。
You hear the traffic. All the senses are involved.
[AI] 你听到了交通的声音。所有的感官都参与其中。
And you're waiting for your girl.
[AI] 你在等你的女孩。
And it's that Tuesday evening back in 1982.
[AI] 那是1982年的那个星期二晚上。
The temporal lobe hallucinations are all sense hallucinations.
[AI] 颞叶幻觉都是感觉幻觉。
full of feeling. full of familiarity.
[AI] 充满感情。非常熟悉。
located in space and time.
[AI] 位于空间和时间上。
coherent. dramatic.
[AI] 连贯的戏剧性的
The Charles Bonnet ones are quite different.
[AI] 查尔斯·博内特的完全不同。
In the Charles Bonnet hallucinations. you have all sorts of levels.
[AI] 在查尔斯·邦尼的幻觉中。你有各种级别。
from the geometrical hallucinations --
[AI] 来自几何幻觉--
the pink and blue squares the woman had --
[AI] 那个女人有粉色和蓝色的正方形--
up to quite elaborate hallucinations
[AI] 达到相当复杂的幻觉
with figures and especially faces.
[AI] 有身材，尤其是脸。
Faces. and sometimes deformed faces.
[AI] 面孔。有时还有变形的脸。
are the single commonest thing in these hallucinations.
[AI] 是这些幻觉中最常见的事情。
And one of the second commonest is cartoons.
[AI] 第二常见的是卡通片。
So. what is going on?
[AI] 所以发生了什么事？
Fascinatingly. in the last few years.
[AI] 令人着迷。在过去的几年里。
it's been possible to do functional brain imagery.
[AI] 有可能进行功能性脑成像。
to do fMRI on people as they are hallucinating.
[AI] 对产生幻觉的人进行功能磁共振成像。
and. in fact. to find that different parts of the visual brain are activated
[AI] 和事实上发现视觉大脑的不同部分被激活
as they are hallucinating.
[AI] 因为他们正在产生幻觉。
When people have these simple. geometrical hallucinations.
[AI] 当人们有这些简单的。几何幻觉。
the primary visual cortex is activated.
[AI] 初级视觉皮层被激活。
This is the part of the brain which perceives edges and patterns.
[AI] 这是大脑感知边缘和模式的部分。
You don't form images with your primary visual cortex.
[AI] 你的初级视觉皮层不会形成图像。
When images are formed.
[AI] 当图像形成时。
a higher part of the visual cortex is involved. in the temporal lobe.
[AI] 视觉皮层的一个较高的部分受到影响。在颞叶。
And in particular. one area of the temporal lobe
[AI] 尤其是。颞叶的一个区域
is called the fusiform gyrus.
[AI] 被称为梭形回。
And it's known that if people have damage in the fusiform gyrus.
[AI] 我们知道如果人们的梭状回受损。
they may lose the ability to recognize faces.
[AI] 他们可能会失去识别人脸的能力。
But if there's an abnormal activity in the fusiform gyrus.
[AI] 但是如果梭状回有异常活动。
they may hallucinate faces.
[AI] 他们可能会产生幻觉。
and this is exactly what you find in some of these people.
[AI] 这正是你在其中一些人身上发现的。
There is an area in the anterior part of this gyrus
[AI] 这个脑回的前部有一个区域
where teeth and eyes are represented.
[AI] 代表牙齿和眼睛的地方。
and that part of the gyrus is activated
[AI] 那部分脑回被激活了
when people get the deformed hallucinations.
[AI] 当人们产生畸形的幻觉时。
There is another part of the brain which is especially activated
[AI] 大脑的另一部分特别活跃
when one sees cartoons.
[AI] 当一个人看到卡通片。
It's activated when one recognizes cartoons.
[AI] 当一个人识别卡通时，它就会被激活。
when one draws cartoons and when one hallucinates them.
[AI] 当一个人画卡通画的时候，当一个人产生幻觉的时候。
It's very interesting that that should be specific.
[AI] 非常有趣的是，这应该是具体的。
There are other parts of the brain which are specifically involved
[AI] 大脑的其他部分也特别参与其中
with the recognition and hallucination of buildings and landscapes.
[AI] 随着建筑物和景观的识别和幻觉。
Around 1970. it was found that there were not only parts of the brain.
[AI] 1970年左右。人们发现不仅仅是大脑的一部分。
but particular cells.
[AI] 但是特殊的细胞。
"Face cells" were discovered around 1970.
[AI] “脸细胞”大约在1970年被发现。
And now we know that there are hundreds of other sorts of cells.
[AI] 现在我们知道还有数百种其他类型的细胞。
which can be very. very specific.
[AI] 这可能是非常重要的。非常具体。
So you may not only have "car" cells. you may have "Aston Martin" cells.
[AI] 所以你可能不仅仅有“汽车”细胞。你可能有“阿斯顿马丁”手机。
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
I saw an Aston Martin this morning. I had to bring it in.
[AI] 今天早上我看到一辆阿斯顿马丁。我必须把它带进来。
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
And now it's in there. somewhere.
[AI] 现在它就在那里。在某处
So --
[AI] 所以--
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
now. at this level. in what's called the inferotemporal cortex.
[AI] 现在在这个层次上。在所谓的下颞叶皮层。
there are only visual images.
[AI] 只有视觉图像。
or figments or fragments.
[AI] 或虚构或碎片。
It's only at higher levels that the other senses join in
[AI] 只有在更高的层次上，其他感官才能参与进来
and there are connections with memory and emotion.
[AI] 这与记忆和情感有关。
And in the Charles Bonnet syndrome.
[AI] 查尔斯·博内特综合症。
you don't go to those higher levels.
[AI] 你不能进入更高的层次。
You're in these levels of inferior visual cortex.
[AI] 你处于这些水平的下视皮层。
where you have thousands and tens of thousands
[AI] 那里有成千上万的人
and millions of images.
[AI] 还有数百万张图片。
or figments or fragmentary figments.
[AI] 或虚构或零碎的虚构。
all neurally encoded in particular cells or small clusters of cells.
[AI] 所有的神经细胞都编码在特定的细胞或小的细胞簇中。
Normally. these are all part of the integrated stream of perception.
[AI] 正常地这些都是综合感知流的一部分。
or imagination.
[AI] 或者想象。
and one is not conscious of them.
[AI] 一个人没有意识到它们。
It is only if one is visually impaired or blind
[AI] 只有当一个人是视力受损或失明的时候
that the process is interrupted.
[AI] 这个过程被打断了。
And instead of getting normal perception.
[AI] 而不是得到正常的感知。
you're getting an anarchic.
[AI] 你会变成一个无政府主义者。
convulsive stimulation. or release.
[AI] 痉挛性刺激。或者释放。
of all of these visual cells in the inferotemporal cortex.
[AI] 在下颞叶皮层的所有这些视觉细胞中。
So. suddenly. you see a face. Suddenly. you see a car.
[AI] 所以突然你看到一张脸。突然你看到一辆车。
Suddenly this and suddenly that.
[AI] 忽此忽彼。
The mind does its best to organize
[AI] 头脑尽最大努力组织起来
and to give some sort of coherence to this.
[AI] 为了给这一点提供某种连贯性。
but not terribly successfully.
[AI] 但并不十分成功。
When these were first described.
[AI] 当这些第一次被描述的时候。
it was thought that they could be interpreted like dreams.
[AI] 人们认为它们可以被解释为梦。
But. in fact. people say.
[AI] 但是事实上人们说。
"I don't recognize the people. I can't form any associations.
[AI] “我不认识这些人，我不能建立任何联系。
Kermit means nothing to me."
[AI] 克米特对我来说毫无意义。"
You don't get anywhere. thinking of them as dreams.
[AI] 你哪儿也去不了。把它们当作梦。
Well. I've more or less said what I wanted.
[AI] 好我或多或少说了我想要的。
I think I just want to recapitulate and say this is common.
[AI] 我想我只是想重述一下，说这很普遍。
Think of the number of blind people.
[AI] 想想盲人的数量。
There must be hundreds of thousands of blind people
[AI] 肯定有成千上万的盲人
who have these hallucinations
[AI] 谁有这些幻觉
but are too scared to mention them.
[AI] 但是他们太害怕了，不敢提起他们。
So this sort of thing needs to be brought into notice.
[AI] 所以这类事情需要引起注意。
for patients. for doctors. for the public.
[AI] 对病人来说。给医生。为了公众。
Finally. I think they are infinitely interesting and valuable.
[AI] 最后我认为它们非常有趣和有价值。
for giving one some insight as to how the brain works.
[AI] 给人一些关于大脑如何工作的见解。
Charles Bonnet said. 250 years ago --
[AI] 查尔斯·邦尼说。250年前--
he wondered how. thinking of these hallucinations.
[AI] 他想知道怎么做。想想这些幻觉。
how. as he put it. the theater of the mind
[AI] 怎样正如他所说。心灵的剧场
could be generated by the machinery of the brain.
[AI] 可以由大脑的机械产生。
Now. 250 years later.
[AI] 现在250年后。
I think we're beginning to glimpse how this is done.
[AI] 我想我们开始了解这是如何做到的。
Thanks very much.
[AI] 非常感谢。
(Applause)
[AI] （掌声）
Chris Anderson: That was superb. Thank you so much.
[AI] 克里斯·安德森：太棒了。非常感谢你。
You speak about these things with so much insight
[AI] 你谈论这些事情的时候很有洞察力
and empathy for your patients.
[AI] 以及对患者的同情。
Have you yourself experienced any of the syndromes you write about?
[AI] 你自己有没有经历过你所写的症状？
Oliver Sacks: I was afraid you would ask that.
[AI] 奥利弗·萨克斯：我怕你会问这个问题。
(Laughter)
[AI] （众笑）
Well. yeah. a lot of them.
[AI] 好是 啊很多。
And. actually. I'm a little visually impaired myself.
[AI] 和事实上我自己也有点视力障碍。
I'm blind in one eye and not terribly good in the other.
[AI] 我一只眼睛瞎了，另一只眼睛不太好。
And I see the geometrical hallucinations.
[AI] 我看到了几何幻觉。
But they stop there.
[AI] 但他们就到此为止。
CA: And they don't disturb you?
[AI] CA:他们不会打扰你吗？
Because you understand what's doing it. it doesn't make you worried?
[AI] 因为你知道这是怎么回事。这不会让你担心吧？
OS: Well. they don't disturb me any more than my tinnitus.
[AI] 奥斯：嗯。他们不会打扰我，就像我的耳鸣一样。
which I ignore.
[AI] 我忽略了这一点。
They occasionally interest me.
[AI] 我偶尔对它们感兴趣。
and I have many pictures of them in my notebooks.
[AI] 我的笔记本上有很多他们的照片。
I've gone and had an fMRI myself.
[AI] 我自己去做了功能磁共振成像。
to see how my visual cortex is ticking over.
[AI] 看看我的视觉皮层是如何运转的。
And when I see all these hexagons
[AI] 当我看到这些六边形的时候
and complex things. which I also have.
[AI] 和复杂的事情。我也有。
in visual migraine.
[AI] 在视觉偏头痛。
I wonder whether everyone sees things like this
[AI] 我想知道是否每个人都看到这样的事情
and whether things like cave art or ornamental art
[AI] 无论是洞穴艺术还是装饰艺术
may have been derived from them a bit.
[AI] 可能是从他们身上衍生出来的。
CA: That was an utterly. utterly fascinating talk.
[AI] CA:那真是一次彻底的失败。非常迷人的谈话。
Thank you so much for sharing.
[AI] 非常感谢您的分享。
OS: Thank you. Thank you.
[AI] 奥斯：谢谢。非常感谢。
(Applause)
[AI] （掌声）